When virtual machines are used, one determination
to make is how the virtual machines will be
networked.
Most hypervisors have some type of virtual
switch manager, and Hyper-V is no exception.
Within Hyper-V, I will select Virtual Switch
Manager.
Then, I will select New virtual network switch
as I want to set up a testing network for
some new virtual machines.
From here, we have three choices.
External gives the virtual machines using
this switch access to whatever the host PC
has access to, meaning if the host PC has
internet access, so do the virtual machines
using this switch.
With internal, the virtual machines on this
switch have access to each other and the host
machine, but that is it.
Finally, with a private network, virtual machines
will only have access to each other.
Given that a best practice is to keep testing
networks isolated, I will select Private and
then Create Virtual Switch, name it, Private,
and select the OK button.
Switches are then assigned to network adapters
on virtual machines.
To demonstrate this, while I have this Windows
10 desktop off, I will select the virtual
machine and then Settings.
Then, I will select Network Adapter and Add,
choosing the private virtual switch we just
created, select the OK button, and now the
virtual machine has a network adapter on a
private network.